

Kennethcdlc@gmail.com ⋈

Sydney, NSW (0)

github.com/kendlc/



linkedin.com/in/kennethcdlc/





KENNETH **DELA CRUZ**

kendlcdev.netlify.app/

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a software engineer passionate on problem solving and constant learning. With years of experience in electrical engineering and hospitality, I get to transfer my critical thinking, problem solving and creativity skills into the everchanging field of software enginering.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Node.JS • HTML / CSS •

MongoDB • JavaScript •

Ruby on Rails • TypeScript •

> Laravel • React.JS •

Firebase • React Native •

Firestore • Redux.JS •

> SQL • Vue.JS •

PostgreSQL • Ruby

RESTful API • PHP •

Netlify Bootstrap •

Git . Heroku

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly

2018-2019

Master of Project Management

Central Oueensland University

2010 - 2015

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Bulacan State University

WORK EXPERIENCE

SUBIpay | July 2022 - Present **Junior Software Engineer**

- Utilises Typescript, Node.js, React Native, Parse Platform and MongoDB in full stack mobile development.
- Designs, codes and debugs software product.
- Maintains and improves existing codebases.
- Investigates problem areas and come out with solutions.
- Works with the business to implement new product features and functionality in a fast paced agile environment.

General Assembly | 2022 **Software Engineer**

Intensive 12 week (480+ hour) course covering fundamentals in full-stack software development.

- Project 3: Pokemon Quizzr | Github | Live Site
 - Pokemon Quizzr is a web application that features a pokedex, "who's that pokemon" game, and leaderboard. ReactJS, Firestore/ Firebase, and PokemonAPI was utilised to build this fun full stack project.
- Project 2: Expense Trackr | Github | Live Site
 - Expense Trackr application that helps you to organize your finances keeping track of all your expenses and incomes. React JS was utilised to build the frontend and Ruby on Rails for the backend.
- Project 1: Manga-shoppu | Github | Live Site
 - Manga-shoppu is an e-commerce web application made using Ruby on Rails. Admin users can add and edit product details. While users can add products to their carts, have a subtotal and total costs on their cart and checkout.
- Project 0: Tic Tac Toe | Github | Live Site
 - Utilised Javascript, CSS, HTML and jQUery to make a fun TicTacToe game project that lets you play 1v1 and demonstrates a nice responsive UI.

Canva | 2019-2022 **Junior Chef**

Utilised Stakeholder management and communication skills to ensure a positive customer experience.

Dream Makers Construction | 2015-2017 Field Electrical Engineer

- Managed costs and resources to meet construction budget.
- Designed revisions and additional works using AutoCAD.
- Identified labour and material cost revisions on electrical works.